Dominic J Mitchell

Full-Stack Web Designer & Developer Providence, RI Area

dominic.joseph.mitchell.2018@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dominic-j-mitchell

Full Stack developer, specializing in front & back end web design. Business professional who has the drive to succeed. 30 years experience in management, leadership, and 8 years in technology.

Technical Skills

Front end: Back end:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Ajax, jQuery, wire-frames, SASS, Scrum/Agile, Git-Hub, Bash, Git, Handlebars AWS, Ruby on Rails, SQL Heroku, JSON, Node.js, express.js, PostgreSQL, Mongoose, MongoDB

Education

Institute – of – Entrepreneurial & Leadership

*HTML – CSS – JavaScript Web Design & Development

New Horizons Computer Learning Center

*A+, Net+, Sec+, MCP&MCDST Network Support Technician

Community College of Rhode Island

2003

Employment History

Web Design & Developer Fellow GA – General Assembly 10/2018-01/2019

*Twelve week web development immersive program (600hrs plus)

Advanced Support Center Engineer I Cox Communications 01/2013-06/2018

*Lead and trainer, tester new deployments, procedure development, voice, data, video support, networking

Applications Specialist – III Lead/Trainer Up-Source 01/2012-12/2012

*Supporting 3rd party software and hardware applications: troubleshooting, break fix, install.

Consultant/Tech TMC 11/2010-01/2012

*Advice and expertise: management, structure and strategy, IT, marketing, design, build-outs.

CEO Mitchell Construction Inc 04/2004-11/2010

Web Development Projects

https://dominicjosephmitchell.github.io/DJMPortfolio/

- *Trails: Welcome to Southern New England Trails, create an index of the trails that you have experienced.
- *Bucket List: Things you'd love to do with your life, Let's get 'em on paper! Integrate with a third-party location-based API to allow users to search for a location or venue to add to their bucket list items.
- * Tic Tac Toe: A custom front-end JavaScript game engine which connects with a third-party API.
- * Vacations: Multi-page user experience designed photo album for your viewing pleasure.
- * Family Tree: Ancestry database for creation and storing of family data. Add your family tree.

^{*}Associates in Arts Degree

^{*}Design/development, sales, consulting, marketing strategies, project management, leadership.